<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Leveraging Digital Technologies:  How Information Quality Leads to Localized Capabilities and Customer Service Performance</title>
<publication-date>2013-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<email>psetia.uark@gmail.com</email>
<institution>University of Arkansas</institution>
<lname>Setia</lname>
<fname>Pankaj</fname>
</author>
<author>
<email>vvenkatesh@vvenkatesh.us</email>
<institution>University of Arkansas</institution>
<lname>Venkatesh</lname>
<fname>Viswanath</fname>
</author>
<author>
<email>joglekar.supreet@gmail.com</email>
<institution>University of Arkansas</institution>
<lname>Joglekar</lname>
<fname>Supreet</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>Customer service</keyword>
<keyword>capabilities</keyword>
<keyword>information quality</keyword>
<keyword>process</keyword>
<keyword>customer response</keyword>
<keyword>customer orientation</keyword>
<keyword>business value of IT</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the growing recognition of the customer’s role in service creation and delivery, there is an increased impetus on building customer-centric organizations.  Digital technologies play a key role in such organizations. Prior research studying digital business strategies has largely focused on building production-side competencies and there has been little focus on customer-side digital business strategies to leverage these technologies.  We propose a theory to understand the effectiveness of a customer-side digital business strategy focused on localized dynamics—here, a firm’s customer service units (CSUs).  Specifically, we use a capabilities perspective to propose digital design as an antecedent to two customer service capabilities—namely, customer orientation capability and customer response capability—across a firm’s CSUs.  These two capabilities will help a firm to locally sense and respond to customer needs, respectively.  Information quality from the digital design of the CSU is proposed as the antecedent to the two capabilities.  Proposed capability-building dynamics are tested using data collected from multiple respondents across 170 branches of a large bank.  Findings suggest that the impacts of information quality in capability-building are contingent on the local process characteristics.  We offer implications for a firm’s customer-side digital business strategy and present new areas for future examination of such strategies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<fpage>565</fpage>
<lpage>590</lpage>
<coverpage-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol37/iss2/14</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3107&amp;amp;context=misq&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>14</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>3107</articleid>
<submission-date>2013-05-21T14:15:25-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Management Information Systems Quarterly</publication-title>
<context-key>4161629</context-key>
<submission-path>misq/vol37/iss2/14</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="embargo_date" type="date">
<value>2013-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2013-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
<field name="short_title" type="string">
<value>Leveraging Digital Technologies</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>