<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>An Empirical Examination of Individual Traits as Antecedents to Computer Anxiety and Computer Self-Efficacy</title>
<publication-date>2002-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<lname>Thatcher</lname>
<fname>Jason</fname>
<mname>Bennett</mname>
</author>
<author>
<lname>Perrewé</lname>
<fname>Pamela</fname>
<mname>L.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>Self-efficacy</keyword>
<keyword>anxiety</keyword>
<keyword>personality</keyword>
<keyword>negative affectivity</keyword>
<keyword>personal innovativeness</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;To better understand how individual differences influence the use of information technology (IT), this study models and tests relationships among dynamic, IT-specific individual differences (i.e., computer self-efficacy and computer anxiety), stable, situation-specific traits (i.e., personal innovativeness in IT) and stable, broad traits (i.e., trait anxiety and negative affectivity). When compared to broad traits, the model suggests that situation-specific traits exert a more pervasive influence on IT situation-specific individual differences. Further, the model suggests that computer anxiety mediates the influence of situation-specific traits (i.e., personal innovativeness) on computer self-efficacy. Results provide support for many of the hypothesized relationships. From a theoretical perspective, the findings help to further our understanding of the nomological network among individual differences that lead to computer self-efficacy. From a practical perspective, the findings may help IT managers design training programs that more effectively increase the computer self-efficacy of users with different dispositional characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol26/iss4/6</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2638&amp;amp;context=misq&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>6</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>2638</articleid>
<submission-date>2008-12-11T07:21:38-08:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Management Information Systems Quarterly</publication-title>
<context-key>680182</context-key>
<submission-path>misq/vol26/iss4/6</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2002-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>