<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Moving Beyond Intentions and Toward the Theory of Trying:  Effects of Work Environment and Gender on Post-Adoption Information Technology Use</title>
<publication-date>2005-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<lname>Ahuja</lname>
<fname>Manju</fname>
<mname>K.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<lname>Thatcher</lname>
<fname>Jason</fname>
<mname>Bennett</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>Theory of trying</keyword>
<keyword>trying to innovate with information technology</keyword>
<keyword>infusion of information technology</keyword>
<keyword>information technology innovation</keyword>
<keyword>IT use</keyword>
<keyword>intentions</keyword>
<keyword>technology acceptance model (TAM)</keyword>
<keyword>adoption</keyword>
<keyword>stress</keyword>
<keyword>overload</keyword>
<keyword>autonomy</keyword>
<keyword>gender</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Grounded in the theory of trying, this study examines the influence of the work environment and gender on trying to innovate with information technology.  The study extends the innovation diffusion literature by offering a theory-driven explanation for examining trying to innovate with IT and a parsimonious measure for this construct.  Drawing on the theory of reasoned action, we argue that work environment impediments render intentions inappropriate for examining emergent uses of IT. Instead of examining intentions, we introduce the goal-based construct of trying to innovate with IT as an appropriate dependent variable for examining emergent IT use. Statistical analysis supports the reliability and validity of a parsimonious measure of trying to innovate with IT. Analysis focuses on two research questions. First, do perceptions of the work environment such as overload and autonomy influence individuals’ trying to innovate with IT? Second, does gender influence the relationship between perceptions of the environment and trying to innovate with IT?   The model articulates how perceptions of the environment moderated by gender may influence trying to innovate with IT. Results provide evidence that overload and autonomy are antecedents to trying to innovate with information technology. Further, findings confirm that autonomy interacts with overload to determine trying to innovate with IT and that these relationships vary by gender. Implications for research and practice are offered.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss3/5</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2733&amp;amp;context=misq&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>5</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>2733</articleid>
<submission-date>2008-12-15T08:25:41-08:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Management Information Systems Quarterly</publication-title>
<context-key>681835</context-key>
<submission-path>misq/vol29/iss3/5</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>