<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Review:  Power and Information Technology Research: A Metatriangulation Review</title>
<publication-date>2002-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<lname>Jasperson</lname>
<fname>Jon (Sean)</fname>
</author>
<author>
<lname>Carte</lname>
<fname>Traci</fname>
<mname>A.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<lname>Saunders</lname>
<fname>Carol</fname>
<mname>S.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<lname>Butler</lname>
<fname>Brian</fname>
<mname>S.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<lname>Croes</lname>
<fname>Henry J. P.</fname>
</author>
<author>
<lname>Zheng</lname>
<fname>Weijun</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>Power</keyword>
<keyword>politics</keyword>
<keyword>IT use</keyword>
<keyword>IT management</keyword>
<keyword>metatriangulation</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;This study uses a metatriangulation approach to explore the relationships between power and information technology impacts, development or deployment, and management or use in a sample of 82 articles from 12 management and MIS journals published between 1980 and 1999. We explore the multiple paradigms underlying this research by applying two sets of lenses to examine the major findings from our sample. The technological imperative, organizational imperative, and emergent perspectives (Markus and Robey 1988) are used as one set of lenses to better understand researchers’ views regarding the causal structure between IT and organizational power. A second set of lenses, which includes the rational, pluralist, interpretive, and radical perspectives (Bradshaw-Camball and Murray 1991), is used to focus on researchers’ views of the role of power and different IT outcomes. We apply each lens separately to describe patterns emerging from the previous power and IT studies. In addition, we discuss the similarities and differences that occur when the two sets of lenses are simultaneously applied. We draw from this discussion to develop metaconjectures, (i.e., propositions that can be interpreted from multiple perspectives), and to suggest guidelines for studying power in future research.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol26/iss4/7</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2641&amp;amp;context=misq&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>7</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>2641</articleid>
<submission-date>2008-12-11T07:33:21-08:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Management Information Systems Quarterly</publication-title>
<context-key>680189</context-key>
<submission-path>misq/vol26/iss4/7</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2002-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>