<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>A Model of Adoption of Technology in the Household:  A Baseline Model Test and Extension Incorporating Household Life Cycle</title>
<publication-date>2005-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<lname>Brown</lname>
<fname>Susan</fname>
<mname>A.</mname>
</author>
<author>
<email>vvenkatesh@vvenkatesh.us</email>
<lname>Venkatesh</lname>
<fname>Viswanath</fname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>option</keyword>
<keyword>technology adoption</keyword>
<keyword>household</keyword>
<keyword>personal computers</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Individual adoption of technology has been studied extensively in the workplace. Far less attention has been paid to adoption of technology in the household. In this paper, we performed the first quantitative test of the recently developed model of adoption of technology in the household (MATH). Further, we proposed and tested a theoretical extension of MATH by arguing that key demographic characteristics that vary across different life cycle stages would play moderating roles. Survey responses were collected from 746 U.S. households that had not yet adopted a PC. The results showed that the integrated model, including MATH constructs and life cycle characteristics, explained 74 percent of the variance in intention to adopt a PC for home use, a significant increase over baseline MATH that explained 50 percent of the variance. Finally, we compared the importance of various factors across household life cycle stages and gained a more refined understanding of the moderating role of household life cycle stage.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss3/4</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2731&amp;amp;context=misq&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>4</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>2731</articleid>
<submission-date>2008-12-15T08:17:00-08:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Management Information Systems Quarterly</publication-title>
<context-key>681827</context-key>
<submission-path>misq/vol29/iss3/4</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>