<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>Technology Frames and Framing:  A Socio-Cognitive Investigation</title>
<publication-date>2002-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<lname>Davidson</lname>
<fname>Elizabeth</fname>
<mname>J.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>Requirements determination</keyword>
<keyword>frames of reference</keyword>
<keyword>social cognition</keyword>
<keyword>information systems development</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Requirements determination (RD) during information systems delivery (ISD) is a complex organizational endeavor, involving political, sensemaking, and communicative processes.  This research draws on the analytic concept of technology frames of reference to develop a socio-cognitive process model of how frames and  shifts in frame salience influence sensemaking during requirements determination.  The model provides a theoretical and conceptual perspective that deepens our understanding of requirements processes in organizations and of the socio-cognitive basis of power in ISD.  The paper reports on a longitudinal case study, in which four technology frame domains were identified and the influence of frames on project participants&#39; understanding of requirements was traced through eight RD episodes.  Repeated shifts in the salience of the business value of IT and IT delivery strategies frames disrupted project participants&#39; understanding of requirements and contributed to a turbulent RD process.  Analysis of frames and framing helped explain how interpretive power was exercised, yet constrained, in this project. Implications for further research and for practice are considered.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol26/iss4/4</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2636&amp;amp;context=misq&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>4</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>2636</articleid>
<submission-date>2008-12-11T06:59:58-08:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Management Information Systems Quarterly</publication-title>
<context-key>680130</context-key>
<submission-path>misq/vol26/iss4/4</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2002-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>