<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>The History of Texaco&#39;s Corporate Information Technology Function:  A General Systems Theoretical Interpretation</title>
<publication-date>2005-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<lname>Porra</lname>
<fname>Jaana</fname>
</author>
<author>
<lname>Hirschheim</lname>
<fname>Rudy</fname>
</author>
<author>
<lname>Parks</lname>
<fname>Michael</fname>
<mname>S.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>Systems theory</keyword>
<keyword>mechanistic</keyword>
<keyword>organic and colonial systems</keyword>
<keyword>historical research</keyword>
<keyword>interpretive research</keyword>
<keyword>IT function success factors</keyword>
<keyword>IT function failure</keyword>
<keyword>longitudinal study</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;We attempt to use general systems theory (GST) to understand why resources at Texaco’s corporate information technology function consistently did not match its task during its 40-year lifetime. Our interpretation uses mechanistic, organic, and colonial systems metaphors, each with three components. The first is an analysis of a management action system made up of organizational indicators such as Texaco’s revenues, profits, employee numbers, IT budgets, and IT personnel numbers. The second is a narrative of performance versus resource needs in Texaco IT function, which shows a gap between IT&#39;s resources and its expanding responsibilities. The third is a management-perception system, which offers reasons why top management continually misinterpreted IT’s performance as inferior. Our results show that the mechanistic, organic, and colonial interpretations converge. In addition, our GST-based interpretations show how top management might have remedied the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<coverpage-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/8</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2744&amp;amp;context=misq&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>8</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>2744</articleid>
<submission-date>2008-12-15T10:39:35-08:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Management Information Systems Quarterly</publication-title>
<context-key>681991</context-key>
<submission-path>misq/vol29/iss4/8</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2005-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>