<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<documents><document>
<title>A Matter of Life and Death:  Exploring Conceptualizations of Sociomateriality in the Context of Critical Care</title>
<publication-date>2014-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</publication-date>
<authors>
<author>
<email>mrj10@cam.ac.uk</email>
<institution>University of Cambridge</institution>
<lname>Jones</lname>
<fname>Matthew</fname>
<mname>R.</mname>
</author>
</authors>
<keywords>
<keyword>Sociomateriality</keyword>
<keyword>practice</keyword>
<keyword>empirical</keyword>
<keyword>adoption</keyword>
<keyword>interpretive</keyword>
</keywords>
<abstract>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sociomateriality has been attracting growing attention in the Organization Studies and Information Systems literatures since 2007, with more than 140 journal articles now referring to the concept. Over 80 percent of these articles have been published since January 2011 and almost all cite the work of Orlikowski (2007, 2010; Orlikowski and Scott 2008) as the source of the concept. Only a few, however, address all of the notions that Orlikowski suggests are entailed in sociomateriality, namely materiality, inseparability, relationality, performativity, and practices, with many employing the concept quite selectively. The contribution of sociomateriality to these literatures is, therefore, still unclear. Drawing on evidence from an ongoing study of the adoption of a computer-based clinical information system in a hospital critical care unit, this paper explores whether the notions, individually and collectively, offer a distinctive and coherent account of the relationship between the social and the material that may be useful in Information Systems research. It is argued that if sociomateriality is to be more than simply a label for research employing a number of loosely related existing theoretical approaches, then studies employing the concept need to pay greater attention to the notions entailed in it and to differences in their interpretation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
<fpage>895</fpage>
<lpage>925</lpage>
<coverpage-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss3/15</coverpage-url>
<fulltext-url>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3198&amp;amp;context=misq&amp;amp;unstamped=1</fulltext-url>
<label>15</label>
<document-type>article</document-type>
<type>article</type>
<articleid>3198</articleid>
<submission-date>2014-07-31T12:39:59-07:00</submission-date>
<publication-title>Management Information Systems Quarterly</publication-title>
<context-key>5854724</context-key>
<submission-path>misq/vol38/iss3/15</submission-path>
<fields>
<field name="embargo_date" type="date">
<value>2014-07-31T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
<field name="peer_reviewed" type="boolean">
<value>true</value>
</field>
<field name="publication_date" type="date">
<value>2014-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</value>
</field>
<field name="short_title" type="string">
<value>Exploring Conceptualizations of Sociomateriality</value>
</field>
</fields>
</document>
</documents>